

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Details

Accra

Ghana

+233 53 178 0476

nurudeen.karim2016@gmail.com

Links

Portfolio

Github

LinkedIn

Skills

MySQL

HTML & CSS

Node.js

jQuery

SQL

Git

React

JavaScript

TypeScript

Python

Django

Express

PostgreSQL

Jest

NextJS

Profile

Top Rated Freelancer on Upwork with 100% job success rate. Highly motivated software engineer with over 6 years of experience developing full stack applications. Resourceful expert at understanding system design, designing and building efficient and scalable databases, building secure API endpoints and developing user-friendly user-interfaces for desktop and hand-held devices. Able to effectively self-manage during independent projects, as well as collaborate in a team setting.

Employment History

Freelancer (Top Rated), Upwork, Remote

JUNE 2022 - PRESENT

Top Rated on Upwork with 100% job success rate. All the reviews written of my work are 5-star reviews. Upwork profile: https://www.upwork.com/freelancers/~01ebdd30ab2bac138b

Some of my works:

- BuildAprompt: A client wanted a prompt application builder that users LangChain, ChatGPT and other OpenAl models to allow users to create Al prompt apps exactly how they want it. I set up the project and its API routes with NextJS (TypeScript), used Prisma as the ORM used to query a Postgresql database on Supabase. Prompt apps built by users can be accessed through API endpoints from a Node (Express) server. https://main-website-7dvp1ioz0-buildaprompt.vercel.app/
- <u>Sliding Ads App</u>: I built a desktop application that fetches ads from a server and displays them on a screen. I set up the project with ElectronJS and Node. The application caches ads data on the desktop and fetches from the cache whenever internet connection is lost.
- <u>Dynamic certificate</u>: A coding bootcamp needed a web page to generate certificates for bootcamp participants. I built the application with ReactJS and the ContextAPI for state management. https://dynamic-certificate.vercel.app/

Full Stack Software Engineer, GuildBytes Tech Solutions, Tamale

JULY 2019 - MAY 2022

- <u>GuildBytes website</u>: I developed the GuildBytes Tech Solutions website
 (https://guildbytes.com) with the core frontend stack (HTML, CSS, and Vanilla
 JavaScript) and Python (Django) backend. I implemented a bootcamp course
 registration system with payment gateway with Paystack.
- <u>GuildBytes POS Application</u>: I built a desktop a Point-of-sale desktop
 application with ElectronJS and Node. The frontend of the application was built
 with ReactJS and TypeScript, ChartJS for the charts on the dashboard and Redux
 state management.

Trainer (Part-time), OpenLabs (Then NIIT), Tamale

FEBRUARY 2020 - DECEMBER 2021

I taught the MERN stack (MySQL, Express, React and Node), Python Programming, HTML, CSS and JavaScript.

Education

BSc Molecular Biology and Biotechnology, University of Cape Coast, Cape Coast

AUGUST 2010 - JUNE 2014

Recombinant DNA Technology award

• Top 1% graduating students